Baishakhi Ray

Postdoctoral Researcher

Department of Computer Science Voice: (303) 748-2958

University of California Davis Email: bairay@ucdavis.edu

Davis, CA - 95616 http://rayb.info

Research Interest

My primary research interest is Software Engineering with a focus on empirical studies, program analysis, and software evolution. Using techniques from diverse domains including machine learning, natural language processing, and rigorous statistical modeling, I analyze large scale software repositories to understand on-going software engineering practices. This data-driven knowledge helps me to build novel program analysis techniques and development tools to improve software quality and programmer productivity.

Education

Ph. D., Electrical & Computer Engineering, University of Texas, Austin.

August 2013 (GPA: 3.97)

Thesis: Analysis of Cross-System Porting and Porting Errors in Software Projects

Advisor: Miryung Kim

MS, Computer Science, University of Colorado, Boulder.

August 2009 (GPA: 4.0)

Thesis: SecureWear: Securing Wearable Mobile Social Networks

Advisor: Richard Han

B.Tech. & B.Sc., Computer Science & Physics, Calcutta University.

July 2004 (GPA: 3.84, Top 1% in University)

Honors

- Best Practical Paper Award, IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy 2014
- Google Summer of Code 2012
- SIGSOFT FSE 2012 CAPS travel award
- Selected for admission to Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) for graduate study in Physics.
- Jawaharlal Nehru Summer Scholarship for Advanced Research, India 2001. (100 students are selected Nationwide).
- Ranked 6 out of 15,000 students in B.Sc. Physics(Hons.) examination.

Research & Work Experience

University of California Davis, CA, USA

Postdoctoral Research Fellow

Mentor: Prem Devanbu

October 2013 - present

Microsoft Research, Redmond, USA

Research Intern May 2013–August 2013

Mentors: Christian Bird, Nachiappan Nagappan, Thomas Zimmermann

Google Summer Code, Google Inc.

Research Intern May 2012 – August 2012

Mentors: Suzette Person, Neha Rungta, NASA

The University of Texas at Austin, TX, USA

Graduate Student Researcher January 2011–May 2013

Adviser: Miryung Kim

Avaya Research Lab, Westminster, CO, USA

Research Intern May 2008 – Aug 2008

Ericsson Pvt. Ltd. Boulder, CO, USA

Software Engineer February 2009–June 2010

Ixia, Sasken, and Texas Instruments, India

Software Engineer August 2004–July 2007

Selected Publications

Full Length Research Papers

- A Large Scale Study of Programming Languages and Code Quality in Github. B. Ray , D. Posnett , V. Filkov, P. T. Devanbu. In ACM SIGSOFT, 22nd International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE'14), acceptance rate: 22%
- Using Frankencerts for Automated Adversarial Testing of Certificate Validation in SSL/TLS Implementations.
 Brubaker, S. Jana, B. Ray, S. Khurshid, and V. Shmatikov
 In 35th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy, MAY, 2014 (S&P (Oakland) '14), acceptance rate: 13%, Best Practical Paper Award
- Detecting and Characterizing Semantic Inconsistencies in Ported Code. B. Ray, M. Kim, S. Person, N. Rungta. In 28th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering, November, 2013 (ASE'13), acceptance rate: 23%, Nominated for Distinguished Paper award, invited for ASE journal special issue.
- An Empirical Study of API Stability and Adoption in the Android Ecosystem. T. McDonnell, B. Ray,
 M. Kim. In 29th IEEE International Conference on Software Maintenance, April, 2013 (ICSM'13), acceptance rate: 22%
- 5. A Case Study of Cross-System Porting in Forked Projects. **B. Ray**, M. Kim. In ACM SIGSOFT, the 20th International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE'12), acceptance rate: 17%
- An Empirical Study of Supplementary Bug Fixes. J. Park, M. Kim, B. Ray, D. Bae. In The 9th
 IEEE Working Conference on Mining Software Repositories (MSR'12), acceptance rate: 28% Invited to
 the Special Issue of Journal of Empirical Software Engineering (EMSE).

- PTask: Operating System Abstractions To Manage GPUs as Compute Devices. CJ. Rossbach, J. Currey, M. Silberstein, B. Ray, E. Witchel. In Proceedings of the 23rd ACM Symposium on Operating System Principles (SOSP'11), acceptance rate: 17%.
- 8. A Protocol for Building Secure and Reliable Covert Channel. **B. Ray** and S. Mishra. In 6th Annual Conference on Privacy, Security and Trust, 2008. (PST'08).
- 9. WhozThat?: Evolving an Ecosystem for Context-Aware Mobile Social Networks. A. Beach, **B. Ray**, et al., In IEEE Network Magazine Special Issue on Composable context aware services, 2008.
- 10. SecureWear: A Framework for Securing Mobile Social Networks. **B. Ray**, R. Han. In Advances in Computer Science and Information Technology. Computer Science and Engineering, Lecture Notes of the Institute for Computer Sciences, Social Informatics and Telecommunications Engineering, 2012.

Under Submission

- 11. The Uniqueness of Changes: Characteristics and Applications. B. Ray, M. Nagappan, C. Bird, N. Nagappan, T. Zimmermann.
- 12. Assert Use in GitHub Projects. C. Casalnuovo, P. Devanbu, A. Oliveira, V. Filkov, B. Ray
- 13. Detecting and Characterizing Semantic Porting Inconsistencies in Copy and Paste Code. **B. Ray**, M. Kim, S. Person, N. Rungta.

Short Papers

- Repertoire: A Cross-System Porting Analysis Tool for Forked Software Projects. B. Ray, C. Wiley, M. Kim. In ACM SIGSOFT the 20th International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering, Formal Research Tool Demonstration (FSE'12).
- 15. Touch Me wE@r: Getting Physical with Social Networks, A. Beach, Baishakhi Ray, L. Buechley. In 2009 Workshop on Sensor-based Models and Feedback Systems for Social Computing. associated with SocialCom 2009.

Software Releases

- Frankencerts, https://github.com/sumanj/frankencert. Has received 51 github 'stars' as of October 2014.
- Repertoire, https://github.com/baishakhir/RepertoireTool. Forked 5 times in github, published in FSE'12 tool demo track

Teaching Experience

Mentoring:

- Saheel Godhane, Graduate Student, University of California, Davis.
- Casey Casalnuovo, Graduate Student, University of California, Davis.
- Vincent Hellendoorn, Visiting Graduate Student, University of California, Davis.
- Connie Nguyen, Undergraduate Student, University of California, Davis.
- Abilio Oliveira, Undergraduate Student, University of California, Davis.
- Lisa Hua, Graduate Student, The University of Texas at Austin.

- Tyler McDonnell, Undergraduate Student, The University of Texas at Austin.

Guest Lecturer:

- Introduction to Programming and Problem Solving, Fall 2014, University of California, Davis
- Software Engineering, Fall 2013, University of California, Davis
- Software Engineering and Design Laboratory, Fall 2013, The University of Texas at Austin

Teaching Assistant: Mobile Computing, Fall 2010, The University of Texas at Austin

Grader: Operating Systems (Spring'08), Networking (Fall'08), University of Colorado, Boulder.

Academic Services

Program Committee.

- Mining Software Repositories, 2015 (MSR)
- Mining Software Repositories mining challenge, 2015 (MSR challenge)
- India Software Engineering Conference, 2015 (ISEC)
- Foundation of Software Engineering Artifact, 2014 (FSE Artifact)
- OOPSLA Artifact, 2013

Journal Reviewer.

- Transactions on Software Engineering (TSE)
- CSI Journal Computer Standards & Interfaces
- Information and Software Technology

External Reviewer.

- Automated Software Engineering, 2014 (ASE)
- Mining Software Repository, 2012 (MSR)
- OOPSLA 2012

Other.

 Vice President, Graduate Women in Engineering, ECE Department, The University of Texas at Austin

Invited Talks

- Detecting and Characterizing Semantic Inconsistencies in Ported Code. NASA Ames, Mountain View, CA, November 2013.
- Analysis of Cross-System Porting and Porting Errors in Software Projects, Fujitsu Laboratories America, Sunnyvale, CA, January 2014

Media Coverage

- Language Study [1]: SlashDot, The Register, Reddit, InfoWorld, Hacker News.
- Frankencerts [2]: Reddit, Golem, Heise.

References

Premkumar T. Devanbu

Professor

Department of Computer Science University of California, Davis Kemper Hall, 1 Shields Avenue Davis, CA 95616, USA

devanbu@cs.ucdavis.edu

Sarfraz Khurshid

Associate Professor
Electrical and Computer Engineering Dept.
The University of Texas at Austin
1 University Station C5000
Austin, TX 78712, USA
khurshid@ece.utexas.edu

Thomas Zimmermann

Researcher
Microsoft Research
1 Microsoft Way
Redmond, WA 98052, USA
tzimmer@microsoft.com

Miryung Kim

Associate Professor
Department of Computer Science
University of California, Los Angeles
Boelter Hall, 420 Westwood Plaza
Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA
miryung@cs.ucla.edu

Vitaly Shmatikov

Associate Professor
Department of Computer Science
The University of Texas at Austin
2317 Speedway
Austin, TX 78712, USA
shmat@cs.utexas.edu